Previously on the show.
上集說到
Weslie’s mark activated new functions of the Magic Train
喜羊羊的手印
and defeated Wolffy.
成功擊退了灰太狼
After bidding farewell to the residents of Tower Town,
與塔塔鎮的居民告別後
Weslie continues his journey on the Magic Train to find his friends.
喜羊羊駕駛著嘻哈號
Will he successfully reunite with his friends?
他能順利地找回他的伙伴嗎？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Weather Factory."
《奇幻天空島之》
I’m really close to the destination on the radar.
已經很接近雷達顯示的目的地了
I wonder who I’ll find over there.
究竟是誰在那裡呢？
What a huge tree!
好大一棵樹啊
What’s that thing flying towards me?
是什麼往這邊飛來？
Oh, no!
糟…糟了
We have an emergency! The aurora fruit was intercepted.
緊急情況，極光果被攔截了
Stop that aircraft immediately.
馬上去截停空中的飛機
Attention! Please descend immediately.
前面的飛機請馬上降落
Uh, what happened?
發生什麼事了？
Uh, excuse me, could you tell me what this place is?
請問，這裡是什麼地方啊？
This is Weather City.
這裡是氣象城
And that facility right ahead...
而在你們面前的
is the Weather Factory.
是天氣工廠
This is where our weather is created.
是製造天氣的地方
This place is huge!
這裡好大啊
Come on in.
進來
Boss, he’s the one intercepting the weather fruits.
主任，就是他攔截了天氣果
Shall we inform the director?
需要通知廠長嗎？
No, of course not.
不…這種小事，我們自己處理就行了
We can just handle it ourselves.
不用驚動廠長了
You’re right.
也對啊
Hello. My name is Weslie, sir.
你…你好，我是喜羊羊
So, you’re the one intercepting the weather fruits?
就是你攔截了天氣果？
Weather… fruit?
天…天氣果？
This… is a weather fruit.
這，就是天氣果
Come and follow me.
你過來
Look.
看
Weather fruits are an important resource of Weather City.
天氣果是氣象島的重要資源
They come from the weather tree.
它們都來自天氣樹
The weather fruits come in three sizes.
樹上有不同種類的天氣果
There are large, medium, and small-sized fruits.
天氣果分大中小三種規格
When the weather fruits ripen,
每當天氣果成熟
the pelicans come and pick them.
&lrm;都會有專門的塘鵝負責採集
They will then transport the fruits to the factory.
然後運送回工廠裡
At the factory,
工廠裡的天氣果經過機器的沖洗
drying,
烘乾
and waxing.
打蠟
Finally, they get sorted by machines,
再通過機器分類
and delivered to our residents.
送到各家各戶
I want some shaved ice...
我要吃刨冰…
I want some shaved ice…
我要吃刨冰
This is the weather fruits you ordered.
這是你訂的天氣果
Oh, thank you very much.
謝謝
The small ones are useful in our daily life.
小的可以用於居民日常生活
The medium ones are good for cleaning our streets.
中等的則可以用於清潔街道
But all that is just what we do on the side.
但這些只是我們的副業
What the factory actually does is to create weather!
工廠真正的工作是
Have a look.
你看
Are those the large weather fruits?
這些是大天氣果嗎？
That’s correct.
沒錯
The large weather fruits are transported to the top of the factory by machines
大的天氣果會被機器輸送到工廠頂層
and then launched to every corner of the world through cannons,
通過傳輸大砲發射到世界各地
forming different weather patterns.
形成不同的天氣
What you hit earlier was a big weather fruit just like one of these.
而你撞上的就是這種大的天氣果
How about I grow a new one to compensate you?
那我重新種一個賠給你吧
That’s fine. But the one you hit earlier was…
好吧，可是你撞到的
our rare aurora fruits.
是稀有的極光果，一年才出產一批
So, if you’re really serious about growing one,
所以，你要重新種極光果
you will need to stay here for one year.
就得留在這裡種一年
One year?
一年？
Where in the world is this place?
這是什麼地方啊？
Wolffy, why are you taking so long?
灰太狼，還不趕快出來
I’m coming!
來了
There you go again. What’s that thing you’re holding?
你手上拿的是什麼東西啊？
It’s an energy extractor! With this,
能量提取槍，有了它
I’ll be able to take the gem back from the goats.
從小羊手上拿回寶石就不是問題了
The question is... can you even catch the goats?
問題是…你捉得到羊嗎？
Dad, Mom, look over here!
爸爸媽媽，你們看
These fruits look so special.
這些果子好特別
Yes, they are.
喔，真的好特別
Why did it suddenly light up?
這怎麼會發光呢？
Wolffy!
灰太狼
Uh, the fruits in this place are very strange.
這裡的果子真奇怪，還是別亂動
What is it this time?
又怎麼了？
Wolffy!
灰太狼
I… I think I’ll go catch goats!
我…
Weslie, why don’t you start by working with Jackie here.
喜羊羊，你就先跟小傑工作吧
Uhm.
嗯
Before we start, I’ll get a protective vest for you to wear.
工作前我會先給你一件防護服
Why do I need one?
為什麼啊？
Because it’s dangerous here in the factory.
因為工廠裡充滿了危險
The vest protects us while we work,
它能保護員工
so we won’t get hurt from the effects of weather fruits.
這樣就不會被天氣果誤傷了
Oh, that’s amazing!
好厲害啊
Here. This one is yours.
來，這件防護服是你的
Mister Jackie, do you know if there’s any equipment
小傑前輩，你知道有什麼設備 可以盡快種出極光果嗎？
Listen, young man, we have to do things step by step.
年輕人，做事都要按部就班
You can’t rush these things.
不能急於求成，就像人生那樣
So you should wait and work here for an entire year.
所以呢，你還是慢慢地等一年吧
Stop thinking about it.
別想那麼多了
Come on. Why don’t you just help me move these packages out?
來，幫我把這些包裹搬出去吧
Why are there so many of them?
為什麼會這麼多啊？
If I have to work here for a year,
以後在這裡工作
how... how can I find my friends?
我…要怎麼去找夥伴們呢？
It would be great if they’re working in this factory too.
如果我的伙伴也在這個工廠裡就好了
But that’s just... impossible.
不過，不可能有這麼巧合的事情吧？
I can take a break after I’m done with this box.
搬完這箱，就差不多到休息時間了
Did I just see Weslie?
怎麼好像看到了喜羊羊？
Maybe I’m just hallucinating.
難道是我眼花？
Okay, it’s time to get back to work.
好，回去工作
Where could you guys be?
你們到底在哪啊？
Hey, have you heard?
喂，你聽說了嗎？
Another land animal came to our factory.
又有一隻地面生物來了我們工廠啊
Yeah, I heard. The new guy said he was from some grassland.
是嗎？ 他說自己是從那個什麼草原來的
Excuse me, was it Green-Green Grassland?
請問是不是青青草原？
Yes, that’s right.
對…他說自己是從青青草原來的
Maybe they came for me!
啊？難道他們來了？
Where is that person now?
你們說的那個人現在在哪？
I think he’s at the warehouse in area 11.
好像在11區的倉庫呢
Thank you so much.
謝謝你們
This is the place.
是這裡了
Who is it?
誰啊？
Hey, Weslie, why don’t you eat something first?
喜羊羊，你先吃點東西吧
The birds were quite helpful.
小鳥們果然說得沒錯
They told me there were goats in this place.
這裡真的有羊啊
Wolffy... Wolffy is here!
灰太狼
No shouting and running in the factory during working hours.
工作期間，請勿大聲喧嘩與追逐
-Excuse me! -Stop!
-讓一讓 -站住！工廠內禁止追逐與喧嘩
I wonder how everyone is now.
不知道大家現在怎麼樣了？
What if one of them is in danger?
他們要是遇到危險可怎麼辦？
When can I find them?
我要什麼時候才能找到他們呢？
Uh, is that you, Paddi?
懶羊羊？
Ha! Weslie!
喜羊羊
That was really you who I saw this morning.
原來早上我沒看錯
It really is you.
真的是你
How come you’re here too?
你怎麼也在這裡啊？
I’ve been waiting forever for you guys.
我在這裡等你們很久了
I thought you already gave up looking for me.
還以為你們不來找我了
Oh, don’t be silly. Let’s go together and look for--
-當然不會，我們一起去找… -找其他的小羊吧
I almost forgot about Wolffy.
差點把灰太狼給忘了
Take my hand!
把手給我
I knew you’d have a mark too.
果然你也有印記
What are you going to do?
你要幹麼？
Extract the energy from the gem on your hand, of course.
當然是吸你手上的寶石的能力了
Wolffy!
灰太狼
Do you really think...
就憑你 能打倒我這個超級大反派嗎？
Paddi, run!
懶羊羊，快跑
Weslie…
喜羊羊啊…喜羊羊
There’s nowhere for you to run.
看你往哪跑
It’s time, Paddi!
懶羊羊，機會來了
Again?
又來
Wait and see, goats.
小羊們，你們給我等著
I’ll be back!
我一定會回來的
TO BE CONTINUED 2783 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
（未完待續 距離啟航還剩2783天）